travelwisconsin.com 2013-05-09

# Terms of Use | Travel Wisconsin

## Terms of Use, Privacy, and Legal

State of Wisconsin laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records provided by both state and federal laws. These exceptions include the privacy of individuals.

Information collected at this site becomes public record and may be subject to inspection and copying by the public, unless an exception in law exists. During your visit to the Department 's Web site, information that is not readily identifiable to an individual is automatically collected and stored. This information is used solely to improve our Web services. For more detail on our privacy policy, please see the expanded statement following.

 **Information Collected and How It is Used**

If you do nothing during your visit to the Department's Web site but browse or download information, we automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:

The Internet Protocol address and domain name used but not the e-mail address. The Internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol

Address to direct Internet traffic to you;

  * The type of browser and operating system you used and your connection speed;
  * The date and time you visited this site;
  * The Web pages or services you accessed at this site; and
  * The Web site you visited prior to coming to this Web site.
  * If you download a publication, the publication that you downloaded.
  * The actions you took while on the site.

The information we automatically collect or store is used to improve the content of our Web services and to help us understand how people are using our services. The Department analyzes our Web site logs to continually improve the value of the materials available on our site. Our Web site logs are not personally identifiable, and we make no attempt to link them with the individuals that browse the Department's Web site.

If during your visit to the Department's Web site you participate in a survey or send an e-mail, the following additional information will be collected:

  * E-mail correspondence: The e-mail address and contents of the e-mail;
  * Surveys: Any information you volunteered in response to a survey.

The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us. The information is retained in accordance with Wisconsin Open Records Law. We use your e-mail to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to further improve our Web site, or to forward the e-mail to another agency for appropriate action. Survey information is used for the purpose designated.

"Personal information" is information about an individual that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes personal identifiers such as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information.

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily participate in an activity that asks for information (i.e. sending an e-mail or participating in a survey, registering an account or participating in a Blog or subscription to our e-mail newsletters). If you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will in no way affect your ability to use any other feature of the Department's Web site.

If personal information is requested on the Web site or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children on-line or by e-mail will be treated the same as information given by an adult and may be subject to public access.

In the State of Wisconsin, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs: the privacy of individuals is included among these exceptions. Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws.

We strive to protect personally identifiable information by collecting only information necessary to deliver our services. All information collected at this site becomes public record that may be subject to inspection and copying by the public, unless an exemption in law exists.

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Wisconsin Open Records Law or other law governing the disclosure of records, the Wisconsin Open Records Law or other applicable law will control.

You can review any personal information we collect about you. You may recommend changes to your personal information you believe in error by submitting a written request that credibly shows the error. If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact us. In all cases, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. See Contact Information section.

**What is a Cookie**

A cookie is a small amount of data, which may include an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to your browser from a Web site's computers and may either be used only during your session (a "session" cookie) or may be stored on your computer's hard drive (a "persistent" cookie). Cookies can contain data about user movement during the visit to the Web site. If your browser software is set to allow cookies, a Web site can send its own cookie to you. A Web site that has set a cookie can only access those cookies it has sent to you, it cannot access cookies sent to you by other sites.

**Why are Cookies Used on Web sites?**

Cookies are one mechanism for maintaining continuity during a user's visit to a Web site. They allow data to be maintained for users' benefit as they navigate a site. This is referred to as "session" or "state management" cookie. These cookies go away when you terminate your visit to the Web site as they are maintained only in your browser's active memory during your session. Cookies may also be stored on your computer to so that you can be recognized by a Web site on subsequent visits. They can be read by the Web site that set them whenever you enter the Web site. They are often used on Web sites that require you to log in to save you entering all of your log-in information. They may store information on your unique identifier and the areas of the Web site you have visited before. These cookies are stored on your computer's hard drive after you have left your Web site visit and consequently are often referred to as "persistent" cookies.

**Choices about Cookies**

You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.)

**Wisconsin Department of Tourism Practices Regarding Cookies**

The Department uses session cookies. The information on these cookies is retained by the Department, only while the user's session is active, in a table that lists the unique identifiers of those currently using the site. When you return to the Department's Web site, you will be given a new cookie. The Department uses third-party cookies from Google Analytics to track website usage.

The Department's business-to-business Web site, industry.travelwisconsin.com has links to other Web sites. These include links to Web sites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on industry.travelwisconsin.com and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another Web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.

To offer comments about this Web site or to comment about the information presented in this Privacy Notice, please contact the Department's web administrator at the following address: [webmaster@travelwisconsin.com](mailto:webmaster@travelwisconsin.com)

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

The Department reserves the right to modify or supplement this Privacy Policy at any time.

**Wisconsin Department of Tourism Public Records Notice**

It is the policy of the State of Wisconsin that all persons are entitled to the greatest possible information regarding the affairs of government and the official acts of those officers and employees who represent them. The Department of Tourism administers the state’s tourism programs and policies. The Department promotes and advertises tourism sites and attractions in Wisconsin in order to attract tourists to and from within the state. It provides a variety of tourist information services to travelers in Wisconsin. It provides consultation, technical assistance, and other services from the tourism industry. The Department conducts tourism research and reports on state economic and other trends affecting Wisconsin tourism. The Department consists of the Office of the Secretary, Bureau of Technology & Customer Services and the Bureau of Communications & Marketing. Stephanie Klett, Secretary and legal custodian of Department of Tourism public records has delegated the responsibility to act as legal custodian to Molly Delaney. Members of the public may inspect and copy public records of the Department by making an oral or written request for the specific records sought to Wisconsin Department of Tourism, 201 West Washington Avenue, Post Office Box 8690, Madison, Wisconsin, 53708, by facsimile to Molly Delaney at (608) 266-3403 or by phone at (608) 266-2345. The public records of the Department of Tourism are available for inspection and copying during normal business hours. Except for legal holidays (please contact the office in advance), those hours are:

  * Monday–Friday: 7:45 – 11:45 AM and 12:30 – 4:30 PM

Fees for providing copies of public records are $ .25 per page for photocopies; actual and direct cost of any transcription, photographic work or postage; a location fee if the actual direct cost of locating information exceeds $50. Requests which exceed a total cost of $5.00 may require prepayment. All requests will be processed as soon as practicable and without delay.
